guys let's find the perimeter of this
compound figure if you want to try this
on your own positive right now because
I'm going to solve it in three two one
it's nice they gave us all these right
angles but I'm going to get them out of
the way so to find the perimeter we want
to add up all the sides so the width
across the figure is equal to 14. that
means if I added the lengths of these
three sides they will also be 14. to
find the total height I'm going to have
to add 12 to something and let's call
this unknown distance X so the height of
our figure is going to be X Plus 12. and
let's add that to our green stuff next
we have the given sides the 8 and the 12
we can add them to our list as well so
we're almost done with our perimeter but
we have one more piece this yellow piece
right here temporarily let's call it
question mark we know that this X plus
the question mark is going to be equal
to 8. and after we subtract X from both
sides we get the question mark is equal
to 8 minus X and we can change that in
our diagram and let's bring this last
side down to our sum after we add up all
of these we will have the perimeter of
our figure so the the green 14 plus 14
is equal to 28 and the blue 8 plus 12 is
equal to 20. let's bring this yellow 8
up here and this 12 plus 8 is also equal
to 20. let's move the 20 down here and
20 plus 20 is equal to 40. we can move
the 40 up here and the minus X up here
plus X and negative X will cancel each
other out and 28 plus 40 is equal to 68.
that is the perimeter of our figure now
we can give it a label of units and put
a box around it so what I really like
about this problem is X can be anything
between 0 and 8 not including 0 and 8. x
could be one or two or three or five six
or seven or any other number between 0
and 8 and it changes the shape of the
figure just a little bit but all of
these figures have the exact same
parameter 68 units how exciting